knex.com 2017-07-25

# Privacy Policy | KNEX.com - Where Creativity Clicks™

### General Privacy Policy

K’NEX Limited Partnership Group (“K’NEX”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us.  Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.  By visiting [www.knex.com](http://www.knex.com/) you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this privacy policy.

K'NEX does not sell or distribute personal information about visitors to our websites to other organizations. We do not sell, rent, or share our mailing lists with other organizations, except as noted below. We are committed to protecting individuals’ personal data online, and adhere to the Children's Advertising Review Unit (CARU) and Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (called COPPA) guidelines.

K'NEX adheres to the following general principles when processing personal data:

  1. We will only collect personal data for specific and specified purposes.
  2. We will not collect personal data beyond what is necessary to accomplish those purposes.
  3. We will use personal data only for the stated purpose, except as stated below, or with prior consent
  4. We will not transfer personal data to third parties except as stated below, or with prior consent.
  5. We will seek to verify and/or update personal data periodically.
  6. We will honor requests for amendments and changes to personal data.
  7. We will not store personal data in identifiable form longer than is necessary to accomplish its purpose or as required by law, except as stated below.

**This website is operated by:**

K'NEX Limited Partnership Group  
P.O. Box 700  
Hatfield, PA 19440  
1-800-KID-KNEX (1-800-543-5639) (Consumer Relations)  
Email@knex.com (Consumer Relations)  
1-800-822-5639 (Main Offices)

From time to time, we undertake or commission consumer research projects, and we may share personal data with third-party research companies for this purpose. Also, such third-party research companies may host survey data in their databases on our behalf. All data transfers for this purpose will be subject to a written contract between us and the third-party vendor in question. The third-party vendor or partner will not have any authority to use such personal data for any purpose other than as instructed by us.

### Note to Parents

K'NEX has developed its website to be an interesting, stimulating, and enjoyable experience for children, as well as adults.  The purpose of this policy is to help you understand some of the information on the website and how the website operates.  Please discuss this policy with your children so that they will understand how to use the website and the information they may be asked to provide.  K'NEX believes that providing you and your child with information about our website and how we use personal information will help you better protect you and your child's privacy.  If you have any questions about our policy, please contact us at contact us or 1-800-KID-KNEX.  For other questions, please contact our Consumer Relations Department at contact us.

### Children's Online Safety – Important Information For Parents

Please take note of this important information. Guidelines have been established by the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (called COPPA) and Children's Advertising Review Unit (CARU) to protect the online privacy of children. K'NEX is committed to complying with these guidelines and regulations for online privacy and security. We'd like you to review this website to make sure you're satisfied with our approach and presentation. K'NEX does not want to collect any information that you, as a parent, are uncomfortable having your child submit to us. K'NEX will rigorously adhere to COPPA policies. COPPA is designed to protect children under the age of 13 by regulating how information may be collected from them, and enforcing strict limits on how that information can be used. COPPA's legal codes also allow for the creation of self-regulation programs within industry groups. K'NEX will rigorously adhere to COPPA policies. COPPA is designed to protect children under the age of 13 by regulating how information may be collected from them, and enforcing strict limits on how that information can be used. COPPA's legal codes also allow for the creation of self-regulation programs within industry groups.

CARU is the self-regulatory group to which our website, knex.com, is subject. CARU has established Self-Regulatory Guidelines for Children's Advertising that account for kids' unique impressionability. Our website, knex.com, adheres to these guidelines. CARU actively monitors advertising and online privacy practices regarding children, seeking voluntary change if a company's advertising or privacy practices are found to be misleading, inaccurate or inconsistent with its Self-Regulatory Guidelines.

Our Safety Guidelines strictly prohibit the posting of information that could personally identify a child, such as their photo, real name, email address, phone number or physical location, unless the parent explicitly agrees to allow such, perhaps in regard to becoming a contest winner, K'NEXpert finalist, etc. We also aim to prevent kids from being exposed to web content that might make them feel anxious or frightened, so we rigorously regulate links to outside websites.

### What Information Does K'NEX Collect?

K'NEX collects information in two ways: (1) Information you provide to us, and (2) Information we collect automatically.

### Information That You Provide

K'NEX may collect information that you provide when you use our website, such as when you: (1) create a profile; (2) make a purchase; (3) participate in contests, events or promotions; (4) send questions or comments via email, or live chat with a K'NEX Consumer Relations representative; (5) submit your resume to us online; (6) complete online surveys; or (7) otherwise communicate with us through the website. The types of personal information that you provide may include your name, email address, telephone number, postal address, credit card information, birth date, and other contact or identifying information that you choose to provide. We may also collect your gender and toy preferences when you provide this information at the same time as your name or other contact or identifying information, or we may combine these data points with your personal information in the future. If you are under the age of 13, only your parent or legal guardian can provide any personal information to us for purposes of registration, and other online activities. See Personal Information Collected from Children under 13 Years Old below for more information.

### Information We Collect Automatically From You

When you access or use knex.com, we also automatically collect information about you. For example, when you visit our website, we collect information about your computer's operating system, Internet Protocol ("IP") address, access times, browser type, versions and language, time zone setting, products you viewed or searched for, page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as clicks), information about the website visit [including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time)], and the URL of the website you visited before navigating to our website (only if you were referred by that site). If you access our website via a mobile device, we may also collect your unique device ID, device make and model, device IP address, mobile carrier, mobile web browser type and version and the location of your device.

### To collect this information, we use the technologies identified below:

**Cookies:**  Cookies are small data files stored on your computer or mobile device by a website. Among other things, cookies help website providers improve their Services and your experience while using their websites.

When you visit the K'NEX website, your computer and our server use a cookie to enable your computer to easily move through our website. We do not otherwise use cookies, collect information with them, or save data associated with them. Your computer retains the cookie, but only in regard to information you entered to purchase from knex.com. For instance, if you added some products to your shopping cart and did not complete the purchase, the selected products will still be on your computer (not ours) the next time you next visit our website. Or, if in response to our initial pop-up notification, you opt to stay on knex.com, instead of being redirected to another K’NEX owned and operated website, the knex.com website will set a cookie to be stored on your computer for a period of 30 days from the date we receive your response to this pop-up notification. This cookie prevents clutter on your screen by disabling this same pop-up notification from automatically reappearing on your screen every time you visit a page on knex.com, during this 30-day period.

If you want to know if cookies have been added to your computer by others - check your settings. Browsers allow you to either accept cookies or refuse them. Refusing cookies may limit a website provider’s ability to provide you improved features and online experiences. You can adjust your browser to tell you when a website tries to put a cookie on your computer. For more information on cookies and how to control or disable them, you may want to visit the following websites:

http://www.aboutcookies.org   
http://www.cookiecentral.com/faq   
http://www.microsoft.com/info/cookies.htm

**Clear GIFs:**  Clear GIFs, sometimes called “pixels,” "web bugs" or "web beacons," are small electronic images that are placed on a web page or in an email message.  K’NEX may use pixels or clear GIFs to monitor user behavior, deliver cookies, collect information, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and to tell if a recipient has opened and acted upon an email.  K'NEX uses pixels, or transparent GIF files, to help manage online advertising.  These GIF files are provided by our ad management partner, Google Analytics™.  These files enable Google Analytics™ to recognize a unique cookie on your Web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website.  With both cookies and Spotlight technology (used by Google), the information we collect and share is anonymous, and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number, or email address. For more information about Google Analytics™, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to www.google.com/analytics.

**Analytics:**  : We use analytics services and software provided by third parties to help us understand how users access and use knex.com. These tools and services may place cookies, web beacons and other devices or technologies on websites to enable them to track traffic data. The data collected typically includes information such as your IP address, your Internet Service Provider, your web browser, the time spent on webpages, the links clicked and the advertisements viewed on those pages. We use this information to improve our website and your experience, to see which areas and features of our website are popular and to count visits.

**Log Files:**  Log files record website activity on our website and enable us to gather statistics about our users' browsing habits. These entries help K'NEX determine (among other things) how many and how often users have accessed or used our website, which pages of our website they've visited, and similar data.

We may associate the information we collect from these technologies with other personal information that you provide for the purposes described in this Policy.

### Information We Collect from Third Parties

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our website. For example, if you create or log into your account through a third-party social networking site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name and any other account information disclosed in accordance with the policies of that third-party social networking site. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical services, advertising networks, analytics providers and search information providers, and may receive information about you from them.

### Third-Party Advertising

We do not allow third parties to place ads on knex.com.  We sometimes engage third parties to place ads for our products and services on other websites, as well as placing ads ourselves. These third parties may place cookies, web beacons and other devices or technologies within the ads.  When you click or scroll over any of these ads, these third parties collect information about your use of knex.com.  The data collected typically includes information such as your IP address, your web browser, web pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and whether you purchased an advertised product.  Third parties may use this information to deliver advertising and/or content targeted to your interests.  For more information about targeted advertising in connection with these third parties, and how to opt out of having your information used in this way, please visit: www.aboutads.info/choices or www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

### Personal Information Collected from Children under 13 Years Old

Under COPPA, the term "personal information" means individually identifiable information about a child that is collected online, such as:

  * first and last name;
  * home or other physical address, including street name and name of a city or town;
  * online contact information, such as an email address;
  * a screen or user name that functions as online contact information;
  * telephone number;
  * a social security number;
  * a photograph, video, or audio file, where such file contains a child's image or voice; and
  * any other identifier that permits the physical or online contacting of a specific child.

Personal information is solicited only on a voluntary basis; it is not required to visit the K'NEX website.

If your child contacts us online, whether it's to join the Kids' Club, participate in a contest, or create a wish list, etc., we collect the child's email address and the email address of his or her parent and/or legal guardian. We will use the parent's or guardian's email address to verify your permission for your child to interact online with knex.com. You, or your child, can terminate these email updates by using the unsubscribe procedure described below.

If you consent to our collection and use of your child's personal information as we describe in this Privacy Policy, it does not mean you are consenting to the disclosure of that information to any outside third party. To do so, we would first need your explicit approval.

COPPA prohibits us, and any other company, from conditioning your child's participation in any activity on our website in exchange for the disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in that activity. We agree with, and adhere to, this rule.

As a parent, you are automatically informed by email when your child contacts us via the K'NEX website. The personal information we have collected from your child via email contact is as follows:

  * Child's first name;
  * Child's email address;
  * Parent/Legal Guardian's email address; and
  * State.

If a parent or guardian does not agree to allow a child to communicate with K'NEX, no communication will be accepted from the child's email address. There is no other action required.

### Use of Information

We use personal information collected through knex.com for purposes described in this Policy or otherwise disclosed to you on or in connection with our Services. For example, we may use your information to:

  * Send you advertising or promotional materials, including information about new products, contests, features and enhancements, special offers and other events of interest from K'NEX and our select partners;
  * Operate and improve our website;
  * Provide and deliver the products and services you request, process transactions, and to send you related information, including confirmations and invoices;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests, and provide customer service;
  * Monitor and evaluate trends, usage and activities in connection with our website;
  * Personalize and improve knex.com, and provide ads, content, communications or features that match user profiles or interests; and
  * Link or combine with other information obtained through third parties to help understand your needs and provide you with better service.

### Sharing of Information

We do not share your personal information with third parties, other than as described in this Policy or in connection with knex.com, with the exception that:

  * If we notify you that the information you provide will be shared in a particular manner, and you provide such information consenting to this disclosure;
  * Information you provide may be disclosed to suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with you;
  * Information you provide may be disclosed to analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimization of our website;
  * Information you provide may be disclosed to third-party vendors, consultants and other service providers who are working on our behalf and need access to your information to carry out their work for us. These entities have agreed to maintain the confidentiality, security, and integrity of the personal information they obtain from us, and, unless we notify you otherwise and provide you with an opportunity to opt-out, will not use your personal information for any purpose other than as described in this Policy; and
  * When we believe it is necessary or appropriate to: (i) comply with applicable law or legal process, or respond to lawful requests or legal authorities; (ii) protect the rights and property of K'NEX and our employees, agents, users and other third parties, including to enforce our agreements, policies and protect against fraudulent, abusive, inappropriate, or unlawful use of our Services; and (iii) protect the safety of K'NEX, our users or any third party.

We may also share aggregated information or information that we have collected from you while on our website, including on co-branded pages (such as when we and another company together have a promotion or contest), and where we have taken reasonable measures to de-identify. We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we may disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.

If K’NEX or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.

If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal information in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our Terms of Use or terms and conditions of supply and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of K’NEX, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

### Where We Store Your Data

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. When we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorized access.

### Social Sharing Features

Knex.com may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools (such as the Facebook® "Like" button or widgets), which let you share actions you take on our website or social media pages with other media, and vice versa. The use of such features may enable the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the third party that provides these features. These features may also collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our website, and may set a cookie to enable the features to function properly. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the third parties that provide these features.

### Linking to Third-Party Sites

To provide relevant information not found on knex.com, facilitate online shopping, and allow you to interact with other websites and/or applications in which you may have accounts (such as Facebook® and other social media sites), K'NEX may provide links or embed third-party applications that allow login from our website to third-party websites. K'NEX will notify users when they are leaving knex.com or otherwise indicate that you will be going to a third-party's site. Your use of these third-party websites and/or applications is subject to the third parties' privacy policies, and we encourage you to read the third parties' privacy policies before submitting personal or other information, or using the websites and/or applications. We do not accept responsibility or liability for these third party policies.

### How to Unsubscribe from knex.com Email Messages

We occasionally have surveys and contests for which we may ask for age, and gender.  You have the right to delete all of this personal information from our records at any time.  You can do this by clicking the "unsubscribe" link below.  The unsubscribe procedure will remove all your, and your child's, personal information from our database. [http://www.knex.com/email-unsubscribe](http://www.knex.com/email-unsubscribe/)

Once we have received and processed your request, you will receive an email notifying you that all of your and your child's information has been deleted from our database.  If you have further comments, questions or concerns about your child's personal information in our email database, or any other concerns, please contact us at our free Consumer Relations phone:  1-800-KID-KNEX (1-800-543-5639), or email us at: [email@knex.com](mailto:email@knex.com).

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.

If your child has emailed us about a problem with a K'NEX product, or has a question regarding a K'NEX toy, the company, or its people, etc., we may categorize and collect that information in generic anonymised categories, so that we can correct problems with the product or instructions, or address concerns, on knex.com's FAQs webpage. We keep this kind of information only in a generic and aggregated form.

We will use any personal information you or your child provides as set out above and in the following circumstances:

  * If we need to respond to an email inquiry.
  * If your child has entered a K'NEX online contest and won, we will need an actual address to send the prize; notification will be sent to the parent's or legal guardian's email address.
  * We may share identified and identifiable information (such as names and email addresses) of those over the age of 18 who have entered a K'NEX website contest, etc., and who have specifically opted in to the sharing of that specific information.

Unless as set out above, never do we sell or distribute information gathered to anyone, nor do we make our mailing lists available to anyone. We might, however, use this information in conjunction with a marketing partner, where we control when and how we use the information. Any information used in this specific manner will be in the categorized and generic format, and will not disclose individual names, email addresses, etc.

It is important for you to make sure your child knows that it is inappropriate to send any personal information to anyone, including K'NEX, unless you have given your explicit approval.

### Secure Online Purchasing from K'NEX

Only those 18 years or older can make an online purchase from K'NEX. The online form requires the purchaser's full name, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, email address and credit card information in order to complete the order. We accept only valid MASTERCARD or VISA credit cards in the name of the purchaser. We submit this information to the credit card company for verification. That credit card information is used only to process and ship the order, and is not retained online after the order has been submitted. The shipping and order addresses and names, telephone numbers, email addresses, and items ordered are kept in a secure off-line database for documentation purposes.

The K'NEX SECURE SERVER connection safely protects Credit Card information via the VeriSign™ system. This information is deleted from your browser after you complete your order. Completion of your order can be done by one of the following: (a) Complete the Credit Card Processing page; or (b) Closing your Web Browser.

K'NEX requires that online orders are submitted by an adult 18 years or older. Any customer younger than 18 years old who wishes to submit an order must have the order submitted by a parent or legal guardian. These orders are the responsibility of the parent(s) or guardian(s) who own the valid credit card used in the transaction. If you have any questions regarding a purchase, please see our Ordering and Shipping Policies section on this page or contact our Consumer Relations Department at 1-800- KID-KNEX (1-800-543-5639), Monday through Friday, 8:30 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. EST (U.S. and Canadian callers only. Please see http://www.knex.com/international-contact to find the Consumer Relations contact information for other countries.).

### Submission Policy - Submitting an Idea or Picture to K'NEX

K'NEX only accepts photos of models for contests, promotions and posting to our Photo Gallery. We do not solicit or accept models or ideas for new products or suggested new models or components. The reason is definitely not hubris in thinking only we can come up with new and exciting ideas: clearly, that would be a ridiculous point of view. Rather, it has to do with conflicts that arise as to the derivation of K'NEX ideas. From time to time, we have people who claim to have invented just about everything we do, including having come up with K'NEX before we did, or they claim that they submitted a concept that was the “inspiration” for something we've later marketed. None of these claims have been even remotely true, but that didn't lessen the aggravation and time that was required to deal with the claims. So, to prevent possible misunderstandings about who owns the rights to products K'NEX sells, anything you send to us will be considered by us as non-confidential and nonproprietary, meaning that you recognize and agree that you are freely giving us the right to use it any way we wish. This may include making and selling products based upon such material, licensing the material to others or posting your ideas/photos on our website and owning the intellectual property rights in and to such ideas.

Kids: If you wish to send any photographs or other materials to K'NEX, you must follow these simple instructions:

  * Discuss this with your parents. They will need to fully read, understand what we've said above, and complete and sign a Permission Form.
  * Photos, pictures or other materials sent to us without a parent's or legal guardian's signature will not be accepted.
  * If you still want to send us pictures, etc., [click here](http://media.knex.com/pdf/photo-gallery/gallery_permission.pdf) for the Permission Form.
  * Send the Permission Form, fully completed and signed by a parent or legal guardian, and the picture, to: 

K'NEX Consumer Relations Department   
P.O. Box 700  
Hatfield, PA 19440

### Review and Update of Personal Information

You can always contact us to review and update personal information we may have stored about you and/or your child.  Please use the following link to contact us.  Please note that before accessing and making changes to your account, we must verify your identity properly.  It may take up to 10 business days for the changes to take effect.

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.
